wilsonlanguage.com 2018-09-02

# Privacy Policy | Wilson Language Training

Wilson Language Training Corporation (“WLT”) has created this Site to provide you with information and access to the educational materials, programs, and services offered by WLT.

We are committed to respecting your privacy. We appreciate the trust you place in WLT. This Privacy Policy constitutes the agreement between you and WLT regarding your provision, and our collection and use of, contact and other information you may provide while using our Site. By using our Site, you consent to this Privacy Policy.

## Table of Contents

  1. Types of Information You Provide
  2. Information That Identifies You: Personally Identifiable Information
  3. How We May Use your Contact Information to Keep You Informed
  4. Information that Does Not Identify You: Aggregate Information
  5. We Use Aggregate Information Only in Ways that Do Not Identify You
  6. How We Safeguard Information
  7. How to Remove Your Information from our Databases
  8. Privacy Protection for Children
  9. Participation in Online Discussions and Recorded Sessions
  10. Links to Other Websites and Social Networking
  11. Required Disclosures
  12. Changes to Privacy Policy
  13. Complete Agreement
  14. Your Consent
  15. Contact Us

* * *

## 1\. The Types of Information You May Provide

Information you may provide while visiting our Site falls into two broad categories: Personally Identifiable Information and Aggregate Information. Personally Identifiable Information is information that can be used to identify or contact you, such as your name, credit card information, email address, or mailing address. Aggregate Information is information that does not identify you, and may include, for example, statistical information concerning the web pages on our Site that users most frequent. Our Privacy Policy governs both categories of information, as detailed below.

Back to Top

## 2\. Information That Identifies You: Personally Identifiable Information

We allow you to decide whether you wish to provide us with Personally Identifiable Information. Accordingly, we have structured our website so that you may visit us, and review a range of information about educational programs and services offered by WLT, without revealing your identity or providing any Personally Identifiable Information.

Some means for gathering personal data include our Online Registration Application for professional learning, Online Employment Application, and our Material Order Form. Users who wish to register for a professional learning program offered by WLT may be asked to provide Personally Identifiable Information, including, but not limited to, first and last name, and birth date. The data obtained through the Application Form is used internally at WLT, and possibly by an associated college or university, for the purpose of providing course credits.

Please note that on occasion, WLT receives inquiries as to whether an individual is Wilson® certified or has otherwise participated in our programs. Our policy is to not disclose personal information about participants in our programs. WLT will however, unless you specifically request otherwise in writing, share information regarding the Wilson® credentials and the level of participation in our professional learning programs.

When you provide information on our Material Order Form to make a purchase, the transactional information that you provide is transmitted in a safe, encrypted format. WLT uses SSL (Secure Socket Layer) technology, an industry-standard protocol used to establish secure communications between a web server and a client. To maintain your security, your encrypted credit card information is sent to the credit card authority and approval status is sent back to us.

You may have the ability on our Site to pose certain questions to staff in order to learn more about services offered by WLT. You may wish to provide us with comments and feedback concerning our Site generally. By communicating with us in these ways, you may provide us with your email address and other Personally Identifiable Information. All data collected is stored at the highest level of security available to our web server.

Back to Top

## 3\. We Use Your Contact Information to Keep You Informed

We may use Personally Identifiable Information you give to us to provide you with information concerning our programs and services, newsletters, updates, and related materials. We may also use this information to respond to questions and comments from you, and to inform you of changes to our Privacy Policy.

You may opt out of receiving email or other information from us, or have your Personally Identifiable Information deleted from our databases by following the directions set out in Section 7 (“How to Remove Your Information from Our Databases”).

We will not sell or disclose any Personally Identifiable Information you provide on our Site to any unrelated third party without your express permission.

Back to Top

## 4\. Information That Does Not Identify You: Aggregate Information

When you browse our Site, the choices you make may provide information concerning your interests, and concerning the appeal and efficacy of associated Site features. Information concerning our visitors’ activities at our Site – which pages they visit, and how long they view these pages, for example – is Aggregate Information. This information does not identify a particular user, but does provide potentially useful data.

### 4A. Cookies

We may collect Aggregate Information about your use of our Site through cookies and similar Internet technologies. If we use cookies, they do not collect or retain your name or other Personally Identifiable Information. In addition, no third parties are permitted to use cookies we may create at our Site for their own purposes. We treat all information that may be collected through cookies and similar Internet technologies as Aggregate Information.

#### Google Analytics

We use a tool called “Google Analytics” to collect information about use of this Site. Google Analytics collects information such as how often users visit this Site, what pages they visit when they do so, and what other sites they used prior to coming to this Site. We use the information we get from Google Analytics only to improve this Site. Google Analytics collects only the IP address assigned to you on the date you visit this Site, rather than your name or other identifying information. We do not combine the information collected through the use of Google Analytics with Personally Identifiable Information. Although Google Analytics plants a permanent cookie on your web browser to identify you as a unique user the next time you visit this Site, the cookie cannot be used by anyone but Google. Google’s ability to use and share information collected by Google Analytics about your visits to this Site is restricted by the Google Analytics Terms of Use and the [Google Privacy Policy](http://www.google.com/policies/privacy/ "Google Privacy Policy").

### 4B. Disabling Cookies

You may choose not to allow us to collect information in this manner, through cookies. If you wish, you can set your browser software to reject cookies. Most browsers provide instructions for disabling the cookies feature in their “Help” section. Because cookies can be used to provide certain functionality, if you disable your browser’s cookies feature, certain elements of our Site may be unavailable to you.

### 4C. IP Addresses

An “Internet Protocol” (IP) address is associated with your computer’s connection to the Internet. We may use your computer’s IP address to maintain contact with you as you navigate through our Site. We also may use your computer’s IP address to provide you with personalized content. Similar to cookies, your computer’s IP address by itself does not identify you personally.

Back to Top

## 5\. We Use Aggregate Information Only In Ways That Do Not Identify You

We may share Aggregate Information, and reports based on this Information, with third parties unrelated to the Site. No information which we provide to third parties will allow anyone to identify you, or determine anything personal about you. For example, we might report to unrelated third parties the number of users of our Site.

Back to Top

## 6\. How We Safeguard Information

It is our intent to protect against the loss, misuse, or alteration of information that we have collected from you. We use a variety of current technologies and processes for protection of our customer data. These systems are structured to deter and prevent hackers and others from accessing this information. Due to the nature of Internet communications and evolving technologies, however, we cannot provide, and disclaim, assurance that the information you provide us will remain free from loss, misuse, or alteration by third parties who, despite our efforts, obtain unauthorized access.

Back to Top

## 7\. How to Remove Your Information from Our Databases

If you request, we will remove your name and other Personally Identifiable Information from our databases. Please understand, however, that it may be impossible to remove this information completely, due to backups and records of deletions. If you wish to remove your name and other Personally Identifiable Information from our databases, please create an email with the term “Remove” in the subject line, and send the email to the address listed in Section 15 (“Contact Us”). As an alternative, you may write to us with your request, at the mailing address listed in Section 15. Please note, however, that some information may be required to be retained by WLT for a certain time period for tax reporting purposes.

Because Aggregate Information does not personally identify our users, we do not provide our users with access to Aggregate Information, and users may not update, revise, or delete any Aggregate Information.

Back to Top

## 8\. Privacy Protection for Children

Our Site is not directed at children, and we will not accept or request personal information from individuals we know to be under 13. In accordance with the Children’s Online Privacy Protection Act of 1998, if we learn that a child under 13 has provided us with Personally Identifiable Information, we will delete this information from our databases.

Back to Top

## 9\. Participation in Online Discussions and Recorded Sessions

If we have a “chat” or “forum” feature on the Site, you may decide to participate in an online discussion. Please keep in mind that any information you provide while participating in an online chat or forum will be available to all participants. These participants, and their transferees, may use Personally Identifiable Information, and other information you disclose in this manner, to contact you and for other purposes. Accordingly, if we choose to provide such features on our Site, we ask that you participate prudently, as this Privacy Policy will not cover the information you disclose in online discussions on our Site.

If you participate in any WLT recorded session, please know that WLT may use the recording only for educational purposes. When a session will be recorded, WLT will notify you and you will have the option not to be included in the recording.

Back to Top

## 10\. Links to Other Websites and Social Networking

To give you access to other helpful information, we may provide links to other sites. We provide these links as a convenience, and WLT does not endorse the content or services offered by, or the privacy policies in place on, these other sites.

Our privacy policy covers only information we collect on our Site. Other sites to which we link may have privacy policies that differ considerably from our Privacy Policy. We have structured our Site to make it reasonably clear when you leave our Site and enter another website. We encourage you to review the privacy policies of each site you visit through our links, to ensure you are comfortable with these policies. We are not responsible for the conduct or policies of these third parties.

WLT may use social networking platforms, such as Facebook, to communicate with our customers. Also, some tools on our Site allow you to share content from our Site through a third party social network. We do not control these social media platforms or your profiles on these services, nor do we establish privacy rules on these sites for how your personal information will be collected or used. If you use these social networking websites or the tools associated with them, please be aware that third party social networking services have their own privacy policies, and we advise you to read them.

Back to Top

## 11\. Required Disclosures

There are two exceptions to our Privacy Policy. First, we may disclose Personally Identifiable Information as may be required in legal proceedings, or in response to a subpoena, court order, or administrative order compelling disclosure. Second, in cases involving a threat of imminent harm to you or others, we may release such information to prevent or mitigate the threat. In any such case, we will seek to limit the scope of disclosure, and will disclose only such information as is reasonably required to fulfill the purpose of the disclosure.

As previously stated, upon request by a third party, and without otherwise disclosing Personally Identifiable Information, we may share information regarding certification and level of participation in our professional learning programs unless we receive a written request from the participant to not share this information.

Back to Top

## 12\. Changes in Our Privacy Policy

From time to time, we may revise our Privacy Policy and we reserve the right to change it at any time. We will notify registered users of these changes, and will post the changes here. Any changes to our Privacy Policy will apply prospectively, and we will maintain Personally Identifiable Information in accordance with the version of the Policy in effect at the time you submitted the information, unless you consent to application of the revised Privacy Policy.

Back to Top

## 13\. Complete Agreement

In addition to this Privacy Policy, your use of our Site is also subject to our Terms of Use. Together with our Terms of Use, this Privacy Policy constitutes the entire agreement between you and WLT with respect to use of the WLT Site.

Back to Top

## 14\. Your Consent

By using our website, you consent to our collection and use of information, in accordance with this Privacy Policy. If you do not agree with the terms of this Privacy Policy, please refrain from becoming a registered user, or from visiting our Site.

Back to Top

## 15\. Contact Us

You may contact us, for any reason, by email as follows: [info@wilsonlanguage.com](mailto:info@wilsonlanguage.com).

You may contact us by mail as follows:

Wilson Language Training Corporation  
47 Old Webster Road  
Oxford, MA 01540

Back to Top

Effective: November 1, 2007; revised February 2010; revised March 2013, April 2015, September 2017, April 2018.   
© 2007, 2015 Wilson Language Training Corporation. All rights reserved.
